Guide to the John W. Gardner Papers SC0908
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2004-188
  - Correspondence Files:
    - Carpenter, Liz, 1971-1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Carstensen, Laura, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Carter, Lisle Jr. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Carter, President and Mrs. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Cater, Douglas, 1970-1993 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Cater, Morrow, 1997-2000 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Catron, Margaret, 1991-1993 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Chandler, Judith, 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Childers, Barry (MANAS), 1994 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Chickering, Lawrence, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Chrislip, David, 1999-2001 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Christopher, Warren, 1993-2000 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Cirone, William, 1980-2000 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Cisneros, Henry, 1993-1999 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Clark, Joseph S., 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Clark, Clifford, 1973-1985 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Cleveland, Harlan, 1970-2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Clever, Linda (1 of 2), 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Clever, Linda (2 of 2), 1979-1999 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Clinton, President and Mrs., 2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Colodzin, Robert, 1973-1994 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Cohen, David (1 of 2), 1995-2001 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Cohen, David (2 of 2), 1980-1994 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Conable, Barber B. Jr., 1970-1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Conn, Stephen, 1993-1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Cordell, LaDoris, 1997-2001 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Cox, Archibald, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Cranston, Alan, 1989-2000 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Craver, Roger, 1994-2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Cronin, Thomas, 1989-1998 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Cuthbertson, Kenneth, 1972-2000 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Cutler, Lloyd, 1970-1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - D, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1989-2001 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Damon, Bill, 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Dayton, Kenneth, 1981-1998 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - DeBusk, Ann, 1987-2001 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Deer, Ada, 1982-2000 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Dietz, Laura, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Morris Doyle Letter – responses, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Dodge, William, 1994-2001 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Drayton, William, 1992-2001 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Drew, Elizabeth, 1970-2000 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Drown, Francesca, 1976-1986 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Duhl, Leonard, 1990-2002 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Dyson, Charles, 1972-1997 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - E, 1988-2000 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Eberle, William, 1969-1999 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Edelman, Marian Wright, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Edelman, Peter, 1971-1996 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Edwards, Leonard, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Edwards, Pat (Mott), 1996-2001 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Eichler, Michael, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Eisenberg, Pablo, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Elworth, Julie, 1991-1993 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Ely, Leonard, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Eshoo, Anna, 1996-2000 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Eson, Morrie, 1991-2000 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Etzioni, Amitai, 1983-1998 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Evans, Eli, 1971-2001 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Evans, Marsha, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Binder: Leadership Papers 1962-1983 (1 of 3) (Box 15, Folder 1 Binder: Leadership Papers 1962-1983 (1 of 3))
    - Binder: Leadership Papers 1962-1983 (2 of 3) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Binder: Leadership Papers 1962-1983 (3 of 3) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Binder: Leadership Bios-1 (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Binder: Leadership Bios-1 (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Binder: Leadership Bios-2 (1 of 3) (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Binder: Leadership Bios-2 (2 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Binder: Leadership Bios-2 (3 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Binder: Studies in Leadership Project (1 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Binder: Studies in Leadership Project (2 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Binder: Studies in Leadership Project (3 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - National Civic League Publications (1 of 5) (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - National Civic League Publications (2 of 5) (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - National Civic League Publications (3 of 5) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - National Civic League Publications (4 of 5) (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - National Civic League Publications (5 of 5) (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - National Civic League-Miscellaneous (1 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - National Civic League-Miscellaneous (2 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - National Civic League-Miscellaneous (3 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - National Civic League-Bound Meeting Agendas (1 of 3) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - National Civic League-Bound Meeting Agendas (2 of 3) (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - National Civic League-Bound Meeting Agendas (3 of 3) (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Binder: John Gardner-Speeches, 1980 (1 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Binder: John Gardner-Speeches, 1980 (2 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Binder: John Gardner speeches 1981 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Binder: John Gardner speeches 1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Binder: John Gardner speeches 1983 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Binder: John Gardner speeches 1984 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Binder: John Gardner speeches 1985 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Binder: John Gardner-Speeches, 1986 (1 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Binder: John Gardner-Speeches, 1986 (2 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Binder: John Gardner-Speeches, 1987 (1 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Binder: John Gardner-Speeches, 1987 (2 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Binder: John Gardner-Speeches, 1988 (1 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Binder: John Gardner-Speeches, 1988 (2 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Binder: John Gardner-Speeches, 1989 (1 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Binder: John Gardner-Speeches, 1989 (2 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications 1970-1971 (1 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications 1970-1971 (2 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications 1972 (1 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications 1972 (2 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications 1973-1974 (1 of 3) (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications 1973-1974 (2 of 3) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications 1973-1974 (3 of 3) (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications, 1974-1975 (1 of 4) (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications, 1974-1975 (2 of 4) (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications, 1974-1975 (3 of 4) (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications, 1974-1975 (4 of 4) (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications, 1976 (1 of 3) (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications, 1976 (2 of 3) (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications, 1976 (3 of 3) (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications, 1977 (1 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications, 1977 (2 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Binder: Common Cause publications, 1977 (3 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Binder: press clippings, 1971 (1 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Binder: press clippings, 1971 (2 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Binder: press clippings, 1971 (3 of 3) (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2008-161
  - The Early Rains [draft], 20 January 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Speeches
    - Speeches and Essays, 1979-1980, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Senate Finance Committee Testimony, 30 January 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Speeches, March-June 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Speeches, September-December 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Speeches, February-June 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Speeches, July-December 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Speeches, January-May 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Speeches, June-November 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Speeches [drafts], 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - White House Fellows Speech, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - World Academy Speech, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - American Leadership Forum Speeches, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - National Society on Aging Speech, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Francesca's 60th Birthday Speech, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Civic Ventures "Coming of Age" Conference Speech, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Independent Sector Speech, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Kauffman Foundation Speech, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Speeches, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Speeches Writings 42, 1990 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Speeches Writings 42, 1990 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Speeches Writings 42, 1990 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Speeches Writings 43, 1991 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Speeches Writings 43, 1991 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Speeches Writings 43, 1991 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Speeches Writings 44, 1992 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Speeches Writings 44, 1992 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Speeches Writings 44, 1992 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Speeches Writings 45, 1993 (folder 1 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Speeches Writings 45, 1993 (folder 2 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Speeches Writings 45, 1993 (folder 3 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Speeches Writings 45, 1993 (folder 4 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Speeches Writings 46, 1994 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Speeches Writings 46, 1994 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Speeches Writings 47, 1995 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Speeches Writings 47, 1995 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Speeches Writings 47, 1995 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Speeches Writings 48, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Speeches Writings 49, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Speeches Writings 50, 1998 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Speeches Writings 50, 1998 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Speeches Writings 51, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Speeches Writings 52, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Speeches Writings 53, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Bortz/Active Living Speech, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Essays, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Essays, March-July 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Essays, September-December 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Essays, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Writings, 1995, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Essays [drafts], 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Northstar, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Writings, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Writings, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - The Old-Fashioned Brainwash (copy 1) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Old-Fashioned Brainwash (copy 2) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Undated Writings (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Life on the Learning Curve," Chapter 1-6 [draft], 1996-2001 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Life on the Learning Curve," Chapter 8-21 [draft], 1975-2001 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Life on the Learning Curve: A John W. Gardner Reader," 2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Common Cause Fundraising Letter Drafts (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Drafts (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - National Civic League Correspondence, 1996-2001 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Haas Center Correspondence, 1987-1999 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Haas Center, 1990-1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Common Cause, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Common Cause Correspondence: Scott Harshbarger 1, 1999-2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Common Cause Correspondence: Scott Harshbarger 2, 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Common Cause Correspondence, 1997-2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Common Cause Luncheon Santa Clara, March 3, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Film Project "John Gardner: Uncommon American" (folder 1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Film Project "John Gardner: Uncommon American" (folder 2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - White House Fellows, 1999-2002 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - White House Fellows Reception, June 23, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - White House Fellows Reception Photographs, June 23, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Haas Center Correspondence 2, 1997-2001 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Gardner [photocopies], circa 1950s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs 1, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Christmas Cards, circa 1940s (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - John W. Gardner at Carnegie [photographs], 1960s (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - John W. Gardner at HEW [photographs], 1960s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Urban Coalition 68-69, 1968-1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - John W. Gardner at Common Cause 1 [photographs], 1969-1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - John W. Gardner at Common Cause 2 [photographs], 1970s (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - John W. Gardner at Aspen Institute [photographs], 1980, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - John W. Gardner at Independent Sector [photographs], 1968-1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - John W. Gardner-various magazine covers [photographs], 1966-1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - John W. Gardner with various Presidents [photographs], 1966-1981 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - John W. Gardner with Mrs. Gardner and Daughter [photographs], 1935, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - John W. Gardner at Graduation Ceremonies [photographs], 1964 and undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Plumber Quote Certificate, circa 1960s (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - John W. Gardner's Family [photographs], circa 1930s-1990s (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - John W. Gardner's House 1965-1989 [photograph], 1969 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - John W. Gardner's-miscellaneous [photograph], undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Common Cause Political Cartoons, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Materials Quoting JWG, 1966-1999 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Articles by/about JWG, 1967-1997 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Articles about Gardner, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets, 1986-1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - White House Fellows Articles, 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - American Leadership Forum Articles, 1993-1996 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Articles by/about JWG, 1994-2001 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Barnacle Article, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Posthumous Mentions of Gardner, circa 2002 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Writings by/about JWG, circa 1950s-1990s (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Durfee Award Nomination, 1971-1982 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Kennedy Center, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1950s (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1990s (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Articles about Gardner, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Articles about Gardner, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - "Citizens Give Ideas in Crisis," Life Magazine, 1/13/1958 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - "Power in Education," New York Times, 7/1965 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Fortune, 10/1965 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Newsweek, 2/28/1966 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Look Magazine, 5/17/1966 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - "Profile of John Gardner," New York Times Magazine, 1/19/1966 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Time Magazine, 1/20/1967 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - "Reorganizing ‘Health' in HEW," Medical World News, 1/26/1968 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - "John Gardner's Own Pursuit of Excellence," Think, Nov/Dec 1969 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - "John Gardner – Thousands of Americans are...," The Washington Post Parade, 11/22/1970 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - The New Yorker, 7/23/1973 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - "The Causes of an Uncommon Citizen," New York Times, 2/9/1977 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - "A Philosophical View of a Capital Career," New York Times, 7/21/1989 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - New York City Tribune, 7/27/1989 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Common Cause Magazine, 9/1989 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - "Gardner Ponders Community," Christian Science Monitor, 10/11/1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "From Public Affairs to Private Life," San Francisco Chronicle, 11/3/1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Leadership group gets pep talk from former Cabinet member" Peninsula Times Tribune, 1/18/1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "The Loss of Leadership," San Jose Mercury News, 1/20/1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "Gardner reflects a life of leadership," Stanford Business School, 9/1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "An Ethnic Patchwork," San Jose Mercury News, June 9, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Sky Magazine, 7/1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Teacher of Truth - John W. Gardner," Caring People, Winter 1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - New York Times, 11/3/1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Times Tribune, 1/26/1992 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Peninsula Times Tribune, 5/11/1992 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - San Jose Mercury News, 5/13/1992 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Chronicle of Philanthropy, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "Disintegration of the Community," Peninsula Times Tribune, 11/24/1992 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - San Jose Mercury News, 1/21/1995 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Community - March 1991 Master (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "Reflections on Youth Leadership," Who Cares, Summer 1996 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - San Jose Mercury News, 2/16/1997 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Council for Excellence in Government, 4/1/1998 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - "Presidential medal winner offers ways of re-building community," Los Altos Town Crier, 6/17/1998 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - San Jose Mercury News, 10/19/1998 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - "Sowing the seeds of renewal," Kauffman Currents, 3/25/1999 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Association Management, 1/2000 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - "The Servant of All Our Purposes," Carnegie Annual Report, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - "Can Organization Dry Rot Be Prevented?" Harper's Magazine, 10/1965 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - "The Antileadership Vaccine," Carnegie Annual Report, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "What Self-Renewal Can Do for Retirement," Think, July/Aug. 1967 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - "Plain Talk About Hatred Violence," Reader's Digest, June 1968 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - "The Talk of the Town," The New Yorker, 2/27/1971 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - "The Things You Learn After You…," Reader's Digest, September 1980 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - "Building Community," Kettering Review, Fall 1989 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "Leadership and the Future," The Futurist, May/June 1990 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - "Building Community," Alternatives, Winter 1990 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - "Renewal and McKinsey," Month by Month, January 1991 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - "Rebirth of the Nation," USA Today, July 1993 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - "Riding the Wave of Renewal," Stone Soup, Fall 1994 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - "Building Community," Celebration Journal, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - "American Renewal," Public Management, Sept. 1994 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - "Wholeness Incorporating Diversity," The Futurist, March/April 1995 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - "We need to strike a spark…,"Governing, July 1995 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - "Rekindling the American Spirit," National Voter, Sept./Oct. 1995 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - "Leadership in the Cities," Leader to Leader, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - "A Call to Build Community," Wingspread Journal, Autumn 1996 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - "Networks of Responsibility," Governing, Oct. 1996 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - "Self-renewal and the meaning of…," The Sacramento Bee, 12/22/1996 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - "Self-Renewal," The Futurist, Nov./Dec. 1996 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - "School and 1996 Community," Community Educ. Journal, 1995/1996 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - "The Experience Corps," Modern Maturity, May/June 1998 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - "In Search of the Fourth Maxim," Western Journal of Medicine, 7/1998 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Community Foundation Silicon Valley Annual Report, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - "National Renewal," National Civic Review, Spring 2000 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - "A Call for Social Cohesion," Perspectives, Sept. 2000 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - "The American Experiment," National Civic Review, Fall 1998 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Stanford Report/Stanford Daily, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Advice to Young Potential Leaders, 4/1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Attributes of Leaders, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Tasks of Leadership, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Commencement, June 16, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Ingredients of Community, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - In Common Cause, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Release of Human Possibilities (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Renewal, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Values, 9/13/1993 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Quotations, 1960s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Building Community, 5/24/1989 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Arthur Page Society speech, 9/25/1989 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - "The Nature of Leadership: Introductory Considerations," Leadership Papers, January 1986 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Gardner Bibliography (articles by), after 1999 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Articles by JWG, 1960s-2000s (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Gardner Bibliography (articles about), after 1999 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Articles by/about JWG, 1968-2001 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "The American Experiment," 4/1999 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Tributes to others, 1990s-2000s (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Awards, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Newsday Article (Leslie Seifert), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Biographical material – Pacific Grove H.S., 1996 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Biographical Info (There Was Light), 1969 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Rand Calendar, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Biographical Information, 1968, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Plumber Quote, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Article by Jennifer Reese, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Commencement, June 1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Quotations, 1991, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous articles about Gardner, 1960s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - New Yorker Articles about Gardner, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Press Clippings, 1980-1981 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Press Clippings, 1980-1981 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Press Clippings, 1980-1981 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Current Bio, 1980s-2000s (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Quotation Booklet-Distribution, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Dulce Carothers' Correspondence- Outgoing, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Dulce Carothers' Correspondence-Incoming, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - JWG Website, 1999-2002 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - "John Gardner: Uncommon American" [Film Project], 2001 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Working Dog Productions (PBS film on JWG), 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Film Project Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - "John Gardner: Uncommon American," [Film Project], 1999-2002 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Rick Stamberger/21st Century Initiative Video Project, 1998-2000 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Film Project Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - JWG Video Transcript, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - "John Gardner: Uncommon American" Promotional Materials, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "Building Community," 1989 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Independent Sector Recognition Banquet, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Photocopies of Pictures of Gardner, 1960s-1970s (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Tributes, Memorials, Obituaries, 2002-2004 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Tributes, Memorials, Obituaries, 1982-2002 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Jossey-Bass (Dorothy Hearst), 2000-2003 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Brian O'Connell Mailing, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Observe, 10/1983 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - "The Dimensions of Leadership," Stanford Business School, Winter 1986 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - The Stanford Daily, 1/7/1991 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Magazine, March 1994 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Business School Magazine, March 1993 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Speeches-Originals, 1976-1990 (Box 13, Folder 16)